Chapter 2: The Unbelievable Night

10:59 pm, June 13th, 1992

The disillusioned bat flew through the forbidden forest, toward where Severus suspected the explosion might come from, at a speed that no non-magical bat could.

Severus used his poorly-developed eyes to guide his general directions and used his echolocation system to try to detect any abnormality in the forest. Severus knew that most magical concealments were meant to deceive human eyes and ears, and some charms would trick human noses, but that was about it. Severus did not know of any existing charm that could guard against the frequencies of a bat echolocation system, except for his own creations, of course. Therefore, in most cases, if his vision and his echolocation system provided him different information, there would most likely be some magical concealments.

However, Severus faced two difficulties.

First, his vision as a bat was far inferior to his sharp eyes as a human being.

And the second was much worse than the first. Namely, as shown in the Azkaban break-out, the Dark Lord had begun to study muggle science. The Dark Lord might learn about echolocation and other types of animal sensory systems that human beings do not possess, and therefore he would create charms against those. Severus could only hope that the Dark Lord had been too busy with his revival to learn about that particular area of muggle science yet.

Then, the discrepancy that Severus hoped for popped up. Somewhere to his east side, probably outside Hogwarts' apparition barrier, there was a large strange area. Though his eyes told him it was just normal woods, his auditory nerves produced an image of something quite different: an open land with some objects scattered here and there. It was too distant for Severus to tell what those things were, but he knew that must be it.

As Severus carefully flew nearer, the image from the strange area became clearer, and the scattering objects looked more and more like tombstones. The disillusioned large bat then realized what this place must be: Tom Riddle Sr.'s real burial place.

-Father's bone, of course! Well, Moody and I spent quite some time in vain.

-So, the Dark Lord will rise again through his father's bone, his servant's flesh, possibly Bellatrix Black's, and his enemy's blood. Damn, that means he must have captured the Potter boy, and will use his blood. Nothing less would satisfy someone as arrogant as the Dark Lord. Then Albus will show up, sacrifice himself to save the big-headed Boy-Who-Lived, and seal the Dark Lord for now.

-Merlin damned stupid Potter! If I survive this, I will personally administer him some potions of my own creation!

But Severus knew he would not survive this. Instead, he would appear at the height of Albus's battle with the Dark Lord, and he would do whatever he could, so that the Boy-Who-Lived would have a chance to escape and perform whatever magic had caused that huge CRACK noise.

Suppressing a sigh, Severus chose a tall tree well outside the range of the discrepancy area, yet close enough for his echolocation system to be effective, and hung upside-down on a branch near the tree trunk like a real bat. He turned his left ear to receive the echoes, and pressed his right one against the trunk. Hopefully, the Dark Lord had not thought of blocking non-air transmitted sound waves yet, and with his magically enhanced auditory system, maybe some sound transmitting through solids could be heard.

As he pressed his right ear harder on the trunk, Severus almost twitched. He clearly heard some footsteps coming from the ground. Being long used to his bat animagus form surveying his surrounding mostly by sound, Severus was able to tell that there were two people, one adult and one child, traveling through a tunnel. And then something swung open; Severus heard his probes bounce off of two figures as they appeared in the graveyard. The taller figure appeared to be Quirrell. Severus vaguely remembered seeing that man before everything became haze a few hours ago, so he was not too surprised that the Dark Lord was in disguise as this David Monroe guy. Plus, that man was the Defense Professor, which made the affair no surprise at all. And the smaller figure, no question, was the Boy-Who-Lived.

Severus was not really surprised to sense an altar rising from the graveyard, either. The Dark Lord had accomplished innumerable mighty magic feats, and this sort of thing was quite normal by his standards.

However, when Severus heard the vague sound coming from the tree trunk, including some mumbling sounding like "Granger shall revive", he almost fell from the tree. Just as Severus was questioning his own sanity, he heard some hissing sound, which in itself was not unusual, since the Dark Lord was the most famous parselmouth in recent history. But why did he talk to the boy in Parseltongue? Just to scare the boy?

-But, but, is my Parseltongue too rusty nowadays? Did I just hear that he spoke in PARSELTONGUE that he wants to revive Granger?

In his misspent youth, Severus had worshiped the Dark Lord, had wanted to mimic the man in every way he could. One of those efforts led to the discovery of one or two parselmouth paintings in forgotten corners of Hogwarts in his sixth year. Imagining himself to be the only servant who could converse with the Dark Lord in Parseltongue, Severus spent quite some time and energy in learning the language. It was almost impossible to distinguish different types of hisses at first, but becoming a bat animagus in the meanwhile did offer him some additional benefits: as a bat, it was much easier to tell the tiny variations in sound. Then back in human form, Severus was finally able to learn the basics of Parseltongue. However, human vocal cords were definitely not designed to make hissing sounds. Severus tried really hard, but until his graduation, he could hardly utter a whole sentence in Parseltongue. When Severus really joined the Death Eaters, he felt himself extremely lucky that he had not boast of his abilities in snake language to anyone: the Dark Lord was too arrogant to accept anyone but himself to master his signature language. Yet, being able to understand some of his master's random hisses did offer Severus competitive edge over his fellow Death Eaters, not to mention that even the Dark Lord could not lie in Parseltongue. But Severus's happy days as a rising star in the Death Eaters soon finished when he realized that the prophecy he had brought to his master might endanger the woman he loved. In haste and in desperation, Severus first begged his master to spare her, then found himself a Light master. The days as a double-agent were no fun at all. If not for his advanced auditory systems and Parseltongue abilities, Severus would have died several times already.

And today, Severus began to doubt both his auditory system and his understanding of snake language: the Dark Lord actually addressed the Boy-Who-Lived as if he could understand Parseltongue as well.

Then it hit him.

-The boy is actually a PARSELMOUTH?!

Before the bat animagus could fully understand the implications of this, he witnessed the creation of an impressive new body for the Dark Lord, and the rise of the nightmarish man. Even knowing that this man would soon be vanquished by Albus, Severus still needed to fight down his chills.

Then Severus realized something else: the Dark Lord did not use Harry Potter's blood, nor his father's bone, nor Bellatrix's flesh. He only used his own preserved blood and the mystical red stone.

Severus had not really walked the walks of really powerful wizards such as Albus Dumbledore or the Dark Lord, but that didn't hinder him from asking himself the obvious questions: what the heck is that stone? The Resurrection Stone? The Philosopher's Stone? And what does it do?

And then Severus witnessed the recreation of Hermione Granger's body, even without a horcrux, only the corpse hidden by the Boy-Who-Lived.

-And with that stone, with that stone…

Severus then realized this stone could be the key to something that he had only dreamed of for so many years: reviving Lily.

After Lily passed away, Severus had been desperate to revive her, but he had no idea how. Of course, if Lily had made a horcrux, it would have been relatively easy, but she was too nice to even think of such a thing. This thought just made Severus sadder. But besides a horcrux, Severus had no idea how one could be revived after their death. There were those so-called sacrificial rituals in plays, and those plays usually ended up in horrible tragedies, in which an ugly sociopathic dark wizard like himself was the clown who got himself possessed by the devil. No, he was not to become that clown. He was to figure out some other way.

Severus knew it was a pureblood tradition to magically preserve their deceased loved ones hair, and some muggles did something similar as well. With some unexplained dim hope, Severus stole some hair from Lily's body before her burial. Though Severus had stopped loving Lily as an idolized lover now, he still dreamed to apologize to a living Lily.

And today, now, it dawned on him: if blood can be used to create new body, if flesh can be used to do the same, then hair…

Now the tradition shared by purebloods and muggles alike made sense to Severus: it must come from an era when revival of somebody's loved ones was much easier, only some blood, or some flesh, or hair, or maybe anything… Yes, a single hair is enough for the Polyjuice potion, so it must be enough for the recreation of a body. Then perhaps I can revive Lily! And Albus! And mother…

Stunned by this realization, Severus almost missed the next important part: the Dark Lord seemed to face something troubling enough for him to allow Harry Potter to have his wand.

-This is not a good sign.

Then Severus heard Harry Potter's shouting:"Expecto PATRONUM!"

Even through whatever the Dark Lord put on for visual deception, even with the bat's poor eyes, he saw the unusual bright white light, the light as a blazing aura of silver fire.

As Severus was trying to figure out what all that meant, he strained to hearsome of the Dark Lord's words: "Your Patronus draws upon your life as well as your magic … happy thought the image of her returning to life … alive … magical …"

Having learnt quite some powerful magic himself, Severus realized that these were the key elements of this ritual, which could only be transferred from one mind to another. Here, now, he was only short of the technicalities of the rituals and the stone, to bring back everyone he loved.

Before Severus could take any joy in this new revelation, he realized that he probably would not live to learn the details, or even survive the next hour.

Severus's heart sank again.

-Perhaps, perhaps the boy will live, and bring back Lily and Albus. As for the oversized bat, well, a Fiendfyre would conveniently burn away everything, including his greasy hair.

Severus gave an internal sigh, and continued to watch as the Dark Lord made Granger a crossbreed of troll and unicorn. It was a very ingenious way to make someone essentially immortal. Severus pondered if he should figure out a way to leave a message of the powerful wizardry he witnessed tonight, but of course that would be all in vain since the knowledge could only pass from one mind to another.

Just as Severus began to curse Merlin's Interdict, things developed quickly: the Dark Lord made a horcrux for Granger, the Boy-Who-Lived tried to kill the Dark Lord with a gun, and failed. But then the Dark Lord still gave Harry Potter detailed instructions on how to resurrect Granger again.

Severus was quite perplexed by the surreal development of things: why would the Dark Lord revive the Granger girl? True, she was kind, brave, and pure, which made her good for the use of a number of rituals, but there are dozens of such girls. Why such trouble?

Then the Dark Lord offered him some answers: "Sseer … prophecy … apocalypsse … girl-child … destruction … "

-Err, according to a Prophecy there would be an apocalyptic disaster if Granger stays dead?

Severus struggled to listen more closely while absorbing this information. It appeared that if Granger stayed dead, the Boy-Who-Lived would bring some disaster to the world.

Then this made quite some sense to Severus. That Potter boy was capable of creating chaos far beyond a first-year's reach. And within a few years, the walking disaster would become a full-grown wizard, Lord of a Noble and Most Ancient house, AND with tonnes of muggle scientific knowledge.

Growing up amongst muggles during the height of the Cold War, Severus was no stranger to the words such as "missile", "atomic bomb", and "nuclear war". When Severus joined the Death Eaters, part of him felt that by conquering the muggle world, the entire world would become much safer – who knew what those mad muggle politicians would do!

Though the Cold War had finished recently, if the way-too-creative Boy-Who-Lived was involved, he might create some horrific disaster in his desperate search for ways to resurrect Granger. Maybe he would think a lot of energy would bring back the dead, and construct a nuclear power plant to get the energy. If that plant blew up, and some muggle government may think they had been nuked, then, then… Well, the current Chernobyl area would seem like a paradise compared to what the world would look like then.

Severus wanted to bang his head against the tree trunk.

-Should I thank the Dark Lord for his great public service?

Then the Death Eaters began to appear in the graveyard. Severus did not feel the call, maybe because he was still supposed to be in the hallucination, trying to rid the evil named Harry Potter from a pregnant Lily.

-Wait, the Dark Lord said in Parseltongue that there is a PROPHECY that Harry Potter may REALLY destroy the world!

Severus felt sicker as he thought of it, and no longer that sure about sacrificing himself to save Harry Potter.

Severus watched dully as Macnair tried to kill the Dark Lord and failed miserably. He might have given that man more credit for his act at any other time, but he was too preoccupied with the prophecy thing.

Then Severus heard some ominous words: "…disposed of Dumbledore…"

-What? NOOO! If Albus is already dead, who would defeat the Dark Lord? Me?! The ELEVEN year old Boy-Who-Lived?!

Severus was so concentrated on the how-to-defeat-Voldemort question, that he could hardly bring himself to reignite his hatred for Sirius Black when heard the bark, and the name "Mr. Grim". He just vaguely berated the idiot aurors who never found out that two Blacks escaped instead of one in the Azkaban episode.

Severus was quite proud of himself in being a powerful wizard - not anywhere near the level of Albus or the Dark Lord, but still quite powerful. He could easily overpower Minerva, and could knock down Filius Flitwick within five minutes in any real fight without stupid rules. Alastor Moody might defeat him with his century of experience, but since Mad-Eye was getting old, Time was on Severus's side. And in the Death Eater ranks, Severus thought only Bellatrix could defeat him in a one-on-one fight, and only a handful could escape. But that was absolutely NOT the same as defeating thirty something Death Eaters AT ONCE, PLUS the Dark Lord.

Severus suddenly hoped he had a really powerful muggle weapon at hand.

-Wait, does the Boy-Who-Lived have a small nuclear weapon on him? And that was what the CRACK about?

Severus faintly remembered something he heard from muggle TV when he ate in some fast food place during the Christmas holidays. It said something about miniaturization of nuclear weapons. Severus had no idea of how small the muggles had made them, nor the power of a "mini" nuclear bomb. And with a shudder, Severus remembered something else from the muggle news: with the collapse of USSR and the end of Cold War, some nations were quite worried that some nuclear weapons may fall into wrong hands. Back then, Severus guessed it would still be quite hard to get one. But if the Dark Lord already got himself a rocket before the Azkaban breakout, it was quite possible that he also got a small nuclear weapon. And by some luck and creativity, the Boy-Who-Lived may get his hands on the trigger.

-Shit.

Before Severus's imagination took him to where the United Kingdom found itself being attacked by a nuclear weapon, thus firing one toward Russia, and the world entering nuclear winter, etc., Severus heard the Dark Lord made the Potter boy take an Unbreakable Vow that he would not destroy the world.

Severus almost could not suppress his gratitude toward his former master. Compared to the potential disaster, the fact that Lucius would lose much of his magic was nothing at all.

When later the Dark Lord tried to extract knowledge from the Boy-Who-Lived, and the Boy-Who-Lived tried to stall, Severus was too emotionally drained to think of any sensible thing to do. He only knew that when it came to time to fight, he would. And that probably would be the end of Severus Snape.

Then Severus heard the fearful hisses coming from Harry Potter's mouth: "…causse huge explossion almosst instantly…"

-NO, NO, NO! It does not matter that the boy thinks the explosion would not destroy the world, nor the Vow would prohibit him from doing anything really dangerous to the world, nor what the real damage this explosion could do! The fact is, the stupid muggles would multiply the damage hundreds and thousands folds by firing missiles toward each other!

Without thinking, Severus left the tree, and flew the fastest he could toward the Boy-Who-Lived, hoping to do SOMETHING to prevent the end of world.

And Severus hit the circle of magical deception, and was stopped by Time.

-Heck, the Dark Lord had set up some ward to prevent this circle's future interacting with its past! Is this going to be the reason that the world ends today?

Distracted by the fate of the world, Severus was still banging his head on the Time barrier when the heads of death eaters began to drop like butterflies, as well as the Dark Lord's hands. And then, Harry Potter's stunning hex hit the Dark Lord.

As the Dark Lord was screaming in pain, the previous pain that had hit Severus twice hit him again. The disillusioned oversized bat dropped from the air. In pain ten times worse than the Cruciatus curse, Severus was only partially aware of the fact that whatever barrier set up by the Dark Lord had went down together with the powerful wizard. Previous "training" from the Dark Lord told Severus not to scream when he was tortured, so the bat instinctively kept his silence. And the Boy-Who-Lived did not notice the sound of a bat dropping to the ground at all, nor the sound of a bat crawling its way to get nearer to him, maybe due to his own pain and fatigue.

In complete amazement, the bat watched the boy as he oblivated the Dark Lord, and then transfigured his body into a steel ring.

Severus let out a sigh of relief.

-You do have to give the boy credit for his creativity. A much better way to temporarily seal the Dark Lord than anything I can think of. PLUS, he did not use any nuclear weapon that would cause chain-reactions in the muggle world.

Severus now could allow himself to survey his surroundings beyond the Dark Lord and the Boy-Who-Lived. But before he could observe the altar for the revival ritual in any detail, he saw Lucius's head right beside him.

Severus felt a wave of nausea. Lucius was not really his friend, at least not the type of friend like Lily, but he had been the only one that he could trust slightly more than other Death Eaters and Slytherins. Plus, they had shared some secrets, and enjoyed some witty talks over expansive drinks.

Severus knew Harry would revive Lily and Albus for sure, and Lord Potter might even revive Eileen Snape if Severus really begged, but Lucius… if he hadn't made any horcruxes, his death would be for real. And since there were rumors that making horcruxes was ominous for one's offspring among purebloods, Lucius probably did not make any.

Severus did not know what he ought to do, but he remembered that the boy said something about keeping Granger's body at five degrees. Silently, Severus transformed back into human shape, and cast a wordless freezing charm on the head beside himself… plus several other heads that he did not resent too much.

Still debating within himself as what he should do with the Death Eaters' heads, Severus saw the Potter boy produce a gas filled weather balloon.

-Oh, that's the sound. Good, a normal gas explosion would not cause a nuclear war. It can't even penetrate my shielding charm.

Then Severus thought of the army of aurors that would come to investigate the graveyard. Needless to say, Mad-Eye and Bones would be among them. He began to have a headache. Not the kind of headache one has for the end of the world, but still quite some headache.

As the Boy-Who-Lived disappeared under the Cloak of Invisibility, and the balloon rose into the air, Severus knew he had about thirty seconds to decide what to do with all the heads.

Just then, Severus heard a hoarse voice beside him, his own voice: "Gather the heads, you idiot! Oh, collect Quirrell, he was possessed by the Dark Lord, who knows how much powerful magic can be gained from his brain. The boy will turn back an hour, and will change his clothes in the first floor boys' bathroom. The instructions and the stone will be in his pouch."

Severus instinctively gathered the frozen heads plus some other parts from various bodies with a wave of his wand, and stuffed them into his own pouch. With some amazement, Severus saw heads identical to those he had gathered flew out from somewhere beside him, and landed at where they had been. And a pouch identical to that of the Potter boy's was handed to him as well as the Stone.

"The Stone can make transfiguration permanent." Severus heard himself. "You know what to do!"

Of course, Severus knew what to do. He would follow the boy, turn back an hour, follow him to the bathroom, swap his pouch and the Stone, do whatever he needed to do within the hour, then come back and remind himself. After that, he would need to get back to the castle quickly again, and pretend to be someone who had just woken up from the nightmarish hallucination.

Notes:

1. According to canon, Parseltongue can be learnt, understood, and even spoken by people who are not Parselmouth by birth. Albus Dumbledore was able to understand that language in Book 6, and Ron Weasley was able to speak it in Book 7 (at least, good enough to open the Chamber of Secrets). Therefore, I assume, with reasonable intelligence and absolute necessity as Death Eater, then a spy against Dark Lord, Severus can understand Parseltongue to a certain degree, and can speak some very broken Parseltongue.

2. I assume that Severus's patronus changed from a doe to a bat after he stopped loving Lily.

3. I assume Severus's understanding of scientific knowledge and muggle society is only up to the level of an average adult muggle who received his education from public schools in a miserable neighborhood, aka, where Severus grew up. So he may know quite something about the nicknames of different drugs, and how to apply for unemployment benefits, but he does not know much science, nor how the muggle world operates outside the dilapidated ex-industrial town.

4. I assume Severus does not know Harry well enough to understand that Harry would revive everyone someday.

Chapter 3: Choice

June 17th, 1993

This was a very normal day for the muggle world. If you were to turn the TV to the news channel, you would only see the normal day-to-day business: squabbles between Democrats and Republicans on the Capitol Hill, continued crisis in the Middle East, civil war in some third-world country that most Americans could not even find on the map, etc.

However, for the wizarding world, this was the one year anniversary since the Boy-Who-Lived and the Girl-Who-Survived put a stopper on Death. – Well, more likely a stopper on wizarding death in the developed and semi-developed world, if you must ask for details.

It was not that the Boy-Who-Lived would reject a dying poor old witch from Afghanistan to be treated by the Stone, it was just that wizards and witches from those places did not trust the western magical community, and there were vivid stories circulating that you needed to sacrifice your soul to gain immortality. - Considering the fact that a lot of those witches and wizards were around when their motherlands were colonies, it was no surprise at all why they might think that. And for some unexplained reasons, witches and wizards from developed countries did not spend much time or energy to clear things up.

Muggleborn and half-blood witches and wizards had brought their loved non-magical ones to be treated in Hogwarts. The Boy-Who-Lived agreed to heal them on the condition that the muggles must be obliviated afterward, and no changes to their appearances would be made. For the doctors who treated the muggle patients previously, they were just unexplained miracles. Some muggle medical journals started to discuss the possibility that they had previously underestimated the self-cure rates of various types of cancer.

When the man, whom some muggle authorities might identify as John Wilson, got up from bed in his tiny government subsidized apartment in Oklahoma City, he thought with some irony that he needed to decide who to revive on this very joyful day for the wizarding world.

The brown-haired, brown-eyed, and flat-nosed man looked at himself in the dirty mirror, and gave a grimace. He was not so pleased with this appearance, nor this identity. Given the choice, he would rather assume the identity of an inconspicuous middle class man with a clean history, so that he could attract less attention from muggle police. Unfortunately, those types of people rarely became nameless corpses in a muggle police morgue. Because he did not want to spend too much energy on hiding this particular identity that Mad-Eye Moody might find out anyway, the man known to Wizarding Britain as Severus Snape settled for a middle aged homeless man who died from drug overdose on a street corner. And it was not that the muggle police absolutely could not find out who the dead drug addict was, they just didn't spend too much energy on the question. With some persuasion and wand movements, a muggle detective soon had John Wilson's social security number, a copy of his birth certificate, medical records, and criminal history ready. Severus raised his eyebrows at the minor mental disability part of the medical records, rolled his eyes on the series of petty thefts and drug offenses, paid the muggle detective handsomely, and oblivated him as a standard procedure. But later, Severus did find the social security checks and food stamps associated with this John Wilson guy rather convenient, for that saved him some trips to the nearest Gringotts bank in Las Vegas, where he could change his gold and silver into US dollars.

Severus drank his morning coffee, changed his eye color from brown to blue, adjusted his nose height and width of his cheekbones, and apparated to an isolated small farm near the Nevada desert. There, he was an upright thirty-four years old farmer named Michael Smith, who was home educated by his parents, and took over the farm after they passed away. It took Severus quite some energy to find such a suitable muggle who unfortunately died from a possible heart attack while working in the fields. Severus frowned at the foul smell of the corpse which had been there for at least three days, but the ease of assuming his identity was worth the price; this guy lived far away from any highway or muggle residence, had no living relatives, and wrote dairies.

Now, John Wilson, Michael Smith, and some other muggles all became small gems in a jewelry box on a wooden table. Severus laid down another box beside it, where there were some other precious stones as well. Finally, from his pouch, Severus pulled out two locks of hair, one red and one black.

Severus wanted to revive his mother and Lily most, but he was not that sure whether his first try on the ritual would be successful. If that failed, Severus was not sure whether it would be counted as "lost in a sacrificial ritual", and could never be regained. No, he could not risk these two lives.

Severus then looked at the box of muggles, whom he did not care much either way. But the problem was, according to the conversation between the Dark Lord and the Boy-Who-Lived, he needed to put some happy thought on hoping them to live rather than die. Severus knew that tricking his own mind to care about those muggles would definitely add more danger to the ritual, so they were out of the way.

As for his Death Eater colleagues, Severus could only name a few that he cared for even a little bit. He didn't like Macnair at all when that man was alive, but he did give the man credit for raising his wand toward the Dark Lord. Yet Severus was not sure that amount of respect was enough. Despite his loathing toward Sirius Black, Severus was on OK terms with Regulus Black before that boy died. What a pity, that boy was not among the stones at hand.

That left only Lucius, literally the most venomous snake known to the wizarding world. Ironically, Severus could trust that man slightly above others exactly for this reason.

When Severus first became a double-agent and a potions master in Hogwarts, he had desperately needed to improve his Parseltongue. One night, the bat animagus flew to the Forbidden Forest in hope of catching a magical snake, so that he could practice the language. When his echolocation system told him about a snake slithering near a small pond, Severus turned back into human form, and hissed to the snake: "K…come b-back wis…with me."

The beautiful blue snake with black strips froze there, as if in shock to see a Parselmouth.

Then Severus realized one moment too late that this was a Blue Krait, which was definitely not a species kept in the Forbidden Forest.

Just as Severus was pulling out his wand, the snake twisted and swirled. A second later, two Death Eaters were pointing their wands at each other.

Before either man could speak or utter a curse, a nearby frog chose this moment to croak, and both animagi had to fight down some very untimely saliva.

Somehow, this moment of awkwardness seemed to lessen the intensity in the air.

Lord Malfoy opened his mouth first, with much better Parseltongue than Severus: "Sssso, we mussst both worship our Lord a great deal."

To that statement, Severus could honestly answer: "Yessss."

Needless to say, Severus was quite aware of the difference between worshiping a powerful lord and being loyal to him. For a long time, Severus had suspected that Lord Malfoy only served the Dark Lord for the interests of House Malfoy, and there were other such speculators among the Death Eaters as well. If Lord Malfoy chose to ask about the loyal question to a random Death Eater in Parseltongue - given the other could speak Parseltongue as well - there was a good chance that the two Death Eaters would have to kill each other afterwards. Severus figured it would be good to let Lucius Malfoy consider him as one such opportunist.

The man with a snake head wand then hissed: "Mussst not let otherssss know, in cassse they are jealousss."

Severus consented to this immediately: "Agreed."

Severus speculated that "they" included the arrogant Dark Lord himself. Of course, Severus would not ask such a stupid question.

Then after quite some hisses, more fluent from Lord Malfoy, and less so from Severus, the two animagi agreed to keep whatever happened tonight as a secret, and would not reveal the other's animagus form or the Parseltongue ability to anyone unless the other one agreed in advance.

Lord Malfoy pondered the black-haired rising star in Death Eaters for a while, then said: "Would be good if we exchange information ssometimesss."

And that was exactly what the double-agent needed, but he could not appear too eager, so he answered vaguely: "Maybe." Then he suggested: "Can ma…make potion for you, for paymentsss. Good po…potioneersss rare today."

Severus hoped he had acted as if he was more interested in Malfoy's money than Malfoy's influence and "friendship".

-Let him think that I am an arrogant young fool who did not quite know my real status.

The white haired man stopped for a while, then replied: "Need to be sssecret. Potionsss ssserve and only sserve their purpossse."

"Of courssse." Severus answered.

Afterwards, Severus had made some interesting potions with dubious legal status for Lucius in exchange for handsome payments. Of course, Severus had to say in Parseltongue that the potions would do and only do whatever they were supposed to do each time. And, acting as if he was somewhat reluctant in the beginning but soon found out how useful this could be, Severus exchanged some not-so-important information and favors with Lord Malfoy. The vague alliance and "friendship" did not get a chance to really develop before the Dark Lord disappeared. In the peaceful years, their "friendship" consisted of mostly potion making for money and occasional small talks, since neither had much useful information for the other.

However, Severus had to admit the alliance did bring him certain benefits. At least, Malfoy house elves made amazing wines and "Cuisses de Grenouille", or so Lord Malfoy would call the French dish. Severus would simply call it frog legs.

During the whole period of this "friendship", Severus did not forget for a single second that you could tell lies with entirely true statements, since he himself was a master of that art. But still, the fact that you could not tell outright lies in Parseltongue did make Lucius slightly more trustworthy than the other Slytherins. Plus, Lucius's son, Draco, was doing some serious jobs in redeeming Slytherin House, which was something Severus desired but could never accomplish himself.

Severus heaved a sigh, and picked up a white stone with blue stripes.

Chapter 5: The First Revival

11:01 pm (Pacific Time), June 18th, 1993

Severus did not know whether the Dark Lord chose approximately this time of day for the recreation of his own body for a reason or not, but he decided to go safe. And since even the Dark Lord would rather prefer his true body for the resurrection of Granger, Severus undid all magical and non-magical concealments, and revealed his black hair, black eyes, and his signature oversized nose.

Beside the Smith family graveyard in their family farm, now laid an altar that Severus created. And upon that altar, there was a white stone with blue stripes. Severus pointed his wand, and said: "Finite Incantatem."

The stone became Lucius' head, preserved at five degree Celsius. The Death Eater's mask had fallen off when Lucius fell down and died, his white hair was cut short around his neck level by whatever magic the Boy-Who-Lived killed all the Death Eaters, and there were blood on his face and white hair.

Severus frowned a bit upon the blood.

-Well, that could be somebody else's blood, which would complicate the whole affair.

The black-haired man waved his wand, and got rid of all the blood. In this way, Lucius looked…more alive. Severus hoped this would help with the ritual. The Dark Lord did say some happy thought about that person being alive was important.

Severus drew in a breath, knowing that this was the most difficult ritual he had ever tried, and spoke: "Flesh, flesh, flesh so wisely hidden."

The obelisks began chanting.

Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma hou emoi (emoi).

Apokatastethi, apokatastethi, apokatastethi to soma hou emoi (emoi).

Flesh and bone oozed out of the neck, creeping forward and solidifying.

As Severus watched the formation of Lucius' shoulder, arms, torso, and legs, he could feel massive magic was drew from the altar, the land, and the air around, and quite some was drew from him. It felt like the type of magic that you could use up and regain, so Severus tried his best to sustain. And Severus understood why the Potter boy had not tried to revive anyone to Severus' knowledge: it just took too much magic the boy did not have yet.

When the last toe was formed, the obelisks stopped chanting.

Severus surveyed the naked form of Lucius in moonlight, and saw a body that was every part as beautiful and perfect as people rumored Lord Malfoy to be, the skin was without blemish, the muscles were well-toned, even his hair grew back to the full length.

-Well, that's some happy thought I can use later.

Then Severus took a chunk of red glass out from his pocket, and laid it upon Lucius' form. Severus knew this might be one of the two places where things could go wrong, but he had no choice.

Back when he just took Potter's pouch, he knew for sure that the Stone was a key item for resurrection. He needed to duplicate the power of the Stone, somehow. He knew he needed a way to cheat, so he pointed his ward to the Stone and said: "Gemino."

An identical looking red glass appeared beside the original one.

Severus knew that items created by the doubling charm would decay over time, and any magical ability of the original item would decay much faster, but since the Stone could make transfiguration permanent… Severus put the original Stone on the fake one, and let it stay there for a minute.

So far as Severus had tested the fake Stone, it seemed to be capable of make transfiguration sustained for at least a year, and this capability could be renewed every ten minutes or so. Severus had transfigured the ear shape of a dog, and the fur color of a cat. Both animals seemed to be fine until this day. But recently, the renewal time of the duplicated stone seemed to get longer, and that was what made Severus really worry.

-Well, if I want to revive Lily, I can just go to the Boy-Who-Lived and ask. And since the boy would prefer Granger had her clothes on…

Severus waved his wand. Lucius' body was lifted to the air and surrounded by dead leaves. A moment later, Lucius was clothed in a Death Eater robe and let down.

Severus frowned a bit at the Death Eater robe, and decided that was not good for any happy thought, so he changed that to an expensive looking formal robe with a wave of wand.

-That looks better now. Then, there is the second difficult part. Use the happy thought of Lucius being alive to fuel a patronus.

Severus tried to gather all his good memories with Lucius, of the delicious frog legs made by Malfoy house elves, of all the witty talks by the fire, of the clicking gold he got from Lucius – no, that's not the right kind of happy memory, especially not the discussions on the interesting effects of certain potions, or the theories of some spells with dubious legal status.

Severus cleared his mind, and tried again.

-The witty talks by the fire over expensive wine, the laugh they had after they successfully set up a trap and got Bellatrix Black into some awkward trouble…

CRAP.

Severus decided to skip the "witty talks" part of his memory.

Then Severus remembered the few moments that Lucius did not appear all that witty or shrewd: the aristocratic patriarch who awkwardly asked if there was any potion that could stop a baby from throwing up the milk after Narcissa "died", the father who explained to his allies why he skipped an important Wizengamot vote to be with his injured son, and the strange man who formed alliance with the Boy-Who-Lived and seemingly helped his son redeem Slytherin…

Severus put all those memory into his magic, and shouted: "Expecto Patronum!"

A bright bat flew out of Severus' wand tip and plunged into Lucius' body.

Nothing happened.

-OK, life and happy thought about a living Lucius.

Severus drew in a breath, and tried again: the awkward aristocratic single father, the man who cared more about his son than a Wizengamot vote, the politician who conceded to his former enemies and helped Draco to redeem Slytherin, the wave of nausea he felt when he saw Lucius' head lying on the ground, the way Draco collapsed and yelled: "Father, NO! Don't die!"

Severus wasn't too sure about the last two parts of his memory, but he tried anyway: "Lucius, come back from death! Expecto Patronum!"

This time, Severus put some of his life into his spell, and saw a round ball much brighter than any patronus he had produced before jumped out of his wand, and entered Lucius' body.

Severus felt a lit bit of his life and magic was lost to that seemingly non-corporeal patronus, and saw Lucius started breathing.

-Errr, what happened to my patronus? Have I just sacrificed its corporeal form? And why is it so bright? Is that some sacrifice as well? Oh, damn Lucius, you'd better be really grateful!

Now Severus looked at the breathing white-haired man, knew he had accomplished something great, and knew maybe this was his moment to walk the walks of great wizards.

Severus smiled to himself, and began to throw all the diagnostic spells he knew on Lucius. All the spells told him that the wizard lying on the altar was healthy in body albeit weak in magic.

-Poor Lucius, I guess I should thank you for your great service to the safety of the world. Oh, well, maybe I should use the memory of the Unbreakable Vow. That's definitely a happy memory for the entire world.

Severus smirked, pointed his wand, and said, "Enervate."

Chapter 8: Friendship of Slytherins

10:05 am, June 22nd, 1993

Severus' transfiguration skills were not as good as Minerva's, nor were his healing skills as good as Madam Pomfrey's, but he was indeed one of the school's transfiguration authorities and Potions Master. During his ten-year tenure in Hogwarts, he had dealt with plenty of "creative" students and even two or three "ingenious" defense professors, and none of them had died on his watch.

Now, Severus was quite worried that his perfect record might break.

Severus knew his quick fixes on the idiots who tried free transfiguration on themselves could last for up to twelve hours, more than enough time to get them to Madam Pomfrey and St. Mungos. But the problem was, those dim-wit cretins usually only tried free human transfiguration on parts of their body. But for Lucius, every part below his neck was transfigured. Even if Severus put all his might into the quick fixes, and applied the duplicated Stone on Lucius for a minute afterwards, things would still go wrong within three to four hours. Afterwards, Severus would need at least one hour of rest to recharge himself.

What made things worse, the fake Stone was losing its power fast. Previously, the power of it could be renewed every ten minutes or so, now it was one hour and counting. Severus suspected that the renewal time would soon be more than four hours, in which case Lucius was definitely doomed.

Even now, when Severus still had time to rest, and the duplicated Stone was semi-working, Lucius had had a cardiatric arrest just two hours after Severus put the fake Stone on him, and Severus had to use his patronus to give Lucius another jump-start.

If Severus still wanted Lucius to live - which he unfortunately did - he needed to get Lucius back to Britain, fast.

The most inconspicuous way was apparition. You could apparate your way from North America to Hogwarts, if you were willing to apparate a couple dozen times, going from Alaska to Russia, from Siberia to Eastern Europe, and finally from France to the United Kingdom. However, taking a fragile Lucius in side-along apparition in such a long journey was obviously a bad idea.

Then Severus was left with two options: the international Floo network, which was controlled by magical governments all over the world; and international Gringotts portkey travelling, which was operated by the goblins. Lucius had said that if what he knew a year ago was still true today, as long as you were willing to pay enough galleons for a first-class portkey, the goblins couldn't care less about who was traveling, or whatever or whoever was in your suitcase.

Therefore, the current plan was that Lucius would enter Severus' suitcase, Severus would take the suitcase, apparate to Las Vegas, make sure Lucius was alright before entering Gringotts, buy a first-class portkey to London, and then apparate to Malfoy Manor.

From what Lucius gathered from the Daily Prophet, Malfoy Manor must have been on high security mode for quite some time, which meant Severus couldn't simply apparate or Floo there without prior permission from either Draco or Narcissa. And if what Lucius was guessing was true, Thief's Downfalls were much more common in Britain these days than before.

Therefore, Lucius had suggested that Severus sent a message to Draco, stating that Severus had a message from Lucius to deliver to him prior to the event that Draco became the next Lord Malfoy, which was technically true. Then, Severus could travel using his true identity.

In his total magical exhaustion and lack of sleep, Severus agreed.

As Severus was writing the letter to Draco with help from the ultimate Malfoy cheating guide, half-mindedly nodding to Lucius' endless praise for his son, some words suddenly caught his attention: "Severus, my brother, would you like to be Draco's godfather?"

Perhaps Severus had had too much coffee and too little sleep during the past two days, but he was no fool. "What do you mean? Macnair was Draco's godfather, if I remember correctly."

Severus almost let it slip that he had Macnair's thumb in his collections, but he closed his mouth in time.

-Does Lucius want me to protect Draco? What an ungrateful bastard! Like saving Lucius' life a couple dozen times is not enough! On the other hand, Draco is redeeming Slytherin…

Lucius then began a tirade about how Severus was indeed his family and his brother now, to which Severus just wanted to put a silencing charm on. And then, "I will never betray you firsst", in Parseltongue.

Severus was suddenly more awake.

-Well, that's a statement that you can hardly expect from a Malfoy. And adding "firsst" to the end of it did make it more true. Maybe the pureblood is more grateful than I thought.

Severus decided to ignore the talking noises regardless. He was just too tired. He may consider Lucius' suggestion after he got some sleep.

But the white-haired man seemed to be quite determined to annoy his one savior. "Severus, this might sound rude to you, but I do have to ask. Is your father a muggle or a squib?"

Severus was too tired and annoyed to hex Lucius now, so he answered: "Muggle. I guess a half-blood is not good enough for Malfoy's godfather after all."

Lucius firmly denied the accusation, and began to explain what he learnt about the Boy-Who-Lived's theory about the inheritance of magic from feeding Draco with Veritaserum, that there was only a single "gene" that determined if someone was magical or not. Two pieces of the gene meant wizards; one piece meant squib; and zero meant muggle.

This oversimplified version of Mendel's pea experiment gave Severus a good laugh: "Oh Merlin, then I must be a squib for sure. And you, saved by a squib! On the other hand, I could be a bastard, which is a happy thought indeed."

-Oh, shit. How did I manage to say the last part out loud?

Severus glanced at the awkward looking blood purist who was busy apologizing, considered hexing him into oblivion, then gave up and dozed off.

Note:

According to canon, Severus Snape, Seamus Finnigan and Lord Voldemort's father were all muggles, not squibs. According to Pottermore, Minerva McGonagall's father was a muggle, and she had two brothers, both of them were wizards. And if Quirrellmort was telling the truth in Chapter 70 of HPMOR, at least he considered his father to be a muggle. If Harry's theory about blood was true or partially true, at least it is not canon compatible, or he has some serious explanations to do with the ultra-high mutation rate. Otherwise, it is possible that none of the half-bloods AND their wizarding parents realized that the non-magic folks in their family are squibs, which means their stupidity and ignorance are beyond my imagination.

Chapter 13: Lucius-Justice

First Private Meeting, Lucius Malfoy, Part II. Justice

After knowing some important secrets, Harry realized the supposed topic of this meeting was actually Lucius' imprisonment. That sneaky snake was pretty good at distractions. "Lord Malfoy, I undersstand that you do not want what you did to become Draco'ss weakness later. With that in mind, what crimess did you commit?"

Lucius' face tightened, then went back to neutral. "Lord Potter, ass for the ensuing legal processs, I need to clarify that I did not conduct all the crimess that I wass accussed of."

Harry did think some of the things people said about Lucius might be exaggerated, but he was still a murderer among other atrocities.

Lucius' face showed a hint of frustration. "Firsst, I have never violated any of the sso-called rape victimss, let alone other crimess of ssuch nature. Karkaroff hass a tasste for strong boyss, not me."

From what Draco told him in the train station, Harry had thought the multiple-rape part of Lucius' crimes were quite likely to be true, but since the man had denied it in Parseltongue - well, Lucius was rich, handsome, young and single, he didn't need violence for his sexual desires; or, Lord Malfoy had done it more discreetly, so no victim actually remembered anything wrong had happened.

And if Harry were to believe everything being said about Lucius' sexual life, then the senior Malfoy was both a male and a female, both a veela and a vampire, both gay and straight, both a sadist and a masochist, impregnated by Voldemort/Grindelwald/Dumbledore/Abraxas Malfoy/fellow Death Eaters/his time-turned self and gave birth to Draco himself… When the rumors got to the point where Albus Dumbledore abducted Narcissa Malfoy because he was jealous and wanted Lucius all for himself, Harry felt it had gone too far and put his foot down on the juicy stories in Daily Prophet and other major magazines. Unfortunately, the Quibbler was still publishing stories such as how Voldemort had a secret daughter with Lucius, and disguised her as a boy named Draco, the Dark Lord failed in his experiment to make Draco a unicorn, and Hermione was revived as a partial unicorn by accident. Harry could still see that Draco needed to exercise extra self-restraint not to hex Luna Lovegood while the girl was saying "Draco, I am so sorry that you lost your father's child, but miscarriage isn't the end of the world."

Then Harry realized why Lucius might appear to be frustrated upon this part of his crimes: some of the more believable part of the stories could be somewhat difficult to explain to the wife that he hadn't seen for eleven years. And soon, Lucius would be locked up, so he probably wouldn't have much chance to repair his relationships with Narcissa for, say, the next several hundred years. Harry didn't mean to cause marriage issues in Death Eater families, but they should have thought of that before they teared other families apart by their atrocities. But it could be hard on Draco.

-And crap, isn't Karkaroff the Headmaster of Durmstrang? If what Lucius said is true, Karkaroff needs to be removed from his position ASAP.

Harry sighed inwardly. "I have no intention to put anything you didn't do on you. As for Karkaroff, evidence?"

"Karkaroff tesstified that I wass in charge of the raid that killed Madam Boness' younger brother'ss whole family except the newborn girl Ssusan Boness, and he alsso claimed that I violated her great-nephew before killing him. Actually, Karkaroff himsself wass the leader of that raid. I wass not even there." Lucius looked quite indignant. "And I wass not in the raid that sslaughtered Monroe family, either. Bellatrix led that one."

Harry was surprised to hear that information in Parseltongue. Those two were the most notorious murders in Lucius' record. Harry could understand why Karkaroff would want to put the Bones case on someone else, but Karkaroff didn't have much motive to frame Lucius on the Monroe case, did he? So Harry asked. "Tell me more about the Monroe casse."

"The Dark Lord ordered uss to kill everyone in the House of Monroe including the housse elvess before David Monroe arrived. I," Lucius said reluctantly, a bit of confusion in his eyes, "I did not undersstand why we should leave the sstrongesst of the family unsscathed. And eradicating old familiess wass not my plan, either. Sso I gave my leader possition to Bellatrix in the lasst minute."

Now Harry saw why Lucius wasn't in the Bones case or the Monroe case: Lucius picked his enemies carefully. If they were ordered to kill a whole family but to leave the strongest and the youngest unscathed, Lucius would not do it. He didn't want to make strong mortal enemies, and he didn't want to fall into literary traps. A true snake indeed.

Then Harry remembered the first murdered that stroke him two years ago in Diagonal Alley. "How about the writer Yermy Wibble and hiss family?"

To that question, Lucius reluctantly nodded. "It was my firsst raid in the Death Eaterss. Bellatrix led the raid, I killed Mrss. Wibble under Bellatrix'ss wand point."

"Did you torture them?" Harry remembered the empty skins. "Or sskin them?"

Lucius' face showed a hint of disgust. "No, I did not. Grayback ate the insside of the three female Wibbless in front of Yermy Wibble, and then Yermy himsself, even Bellatrix was ssick of that. And I tried to sstay away from Grayback ever ssince."

Harry had to suppress his shudder. "And other cassess?"

"Lord Potter, to my undersstanding of British wizarding law," Lucius' face was neutral as well as his voice, "I am not required to prove that I am guilty. But I can asssure you, the number of people that I killed or tortured wass far lesss than what people accussed me of. For example, I am ssure that the hex that I ssent wass different from the one that took Fabian Prewett'ss life, but the battle field wass too chaotic for me to point out who did it. And I never tortured people for pleassure."

Harry listened, and an image of a Blue Krait silently hiding in the darkness emerged in his mind: careful, calculating, patient, dangerous, and deadly. It picked its victims carefully, so that there would be less retributions afterwards. The snake didn't strike for fun, but only because the kill was necessary. Lucius' murder and torture counts might indeed be smaller than what people thought, but that was because Lucius perceived excessive violence as unnecessary and time-consuming, and he evaded the powerful enemies carefully. Harry doubted, with a few exceptions where Lucius couldn't control the situation, none of Lucius' victims had strong family members left alive to revenge for their loved ones.

"Lord Malfoy, I undersstand the law. But I do need to know, how many did you kill?" Harry hesitated whether he should use Draco's name again, but decided against it.

Lucius inhaled, exhaled. "Seven to nine. The firsst posssible one wass before I joined the Death Eaterss, I wass under falsse memory charmss that time, sso I am not really ssure if I had actually killed the muggle. After becoming a Death Eater, I participated in a total of sseven raidss, killed six people in all the raidss. And I have unexpectedly encountered aurorss twice, killed one or two. I am not ssure whether it wass me who killed Gideon Prewett."

-Oh, wait.

"You were under falsse memory charmss in your posssibly firsst kill?" Harry asked in surprise.

Lucius answered reluctantly. "The firsst killing cursse wass imposssibly hard for mosst people. My tutor memory charmed me to think that the muggle he captured killed my mother, sso that I could hate the muggle enough to usse the killing cursse. But ssince I wass memory charmed anyway, I wass not even ssure the entire sscene ever happened. And I sstill felt it extremely difficult to kill Mrss. Wibble when under Bellatrix'ss wand point, sso I probably did not kill the muggle."

Harry fought down a chill in his spine. Whether Lucius actually killed the muggle or not, if Harry were not here to intervene, that would be a lesson that Lucius would arrange for Draco to receive, and Draco's soul/mind would be cracked because of the lesson. Harry had to keep Draco closer to protect him from THAT.

-And seven to nine murders, only the first one might be forced or forged.

Harry focused his attention, and hissed. "My ssuggesstion would be fifty yearss for each account of murder. You might argue for the one you committed under the wand point of Bellatrix that your hand wass forced, but ssince you did ssign up for the Death Eaterss yoursself, it might still account for thirty yearss."

Upon hearing the sentence suggestion of three hundred and thirty years, Lucius' face ashened. He opened his mouth, and closed again. After several seconds of hesitation, Lucius argued for himself. "Wouldn't my contributionss to the general public be counted as a reason for shorter time?"

Harry had always been furious toward the injustice in both muggle and magical legal systems where rich people could get a lesser sentence or even walk free, and the poor had to serve the full time. Harry hissed. "No, gold cannot buy the law, not any more."

Lucius' eyes flinched a bit upon Harry's wrath, but his voice was steady. "Lord Potter, I meant my contribution in the Unbreakable Vow."

-Oh, that. That's actually a valid argument. Even though Lucius was forced to be the binder for the Unbreakable Vow, his magic was still vital for the Vow to stand. Even if only 0.01% of the Vow could be attributed to Lucius, the number of people Lucius potentially saved…

Harry did a quick mental calculation: 0.01% times six billion people on earth, times the four incidences where Harry could have destroyed the world without the Vow, the number is 2.4 million.

Harry wanted to argue further for the compulsory nature of Lucius' involvement, but Ravenclaw quickly pointed out: hey, even though we might have tricked Lucius a bit at the time in Gringotts, if Lucius had not agreed to participate in the deal and returned all our money of his own free will, and if he didn't enforce the changes in Hogwarts and elsewhere, Voldemort would not have picked Lucius as the binder.

Hufflepuff backed Ravenclaw up. Lucius did treat Bones, Crouch, and Longbottom fairly after he signed the deal as far as we know.

Gryffindor argued against them: Lucius also went to the graveyard that night with his own free will. Our priority is to protect Draco from Lucius, so we should lock Lucius up as long as possible, and ban all communications.

Are you sure the reason you want a long prison sentence and a ban on communication is not that YOU want to find an excuse to further manipulate Draco? I am sure Draco would want to write to his father and visit him sometimes. Hufflepuff countered Gryffindor. Plus, a man who has saved 2.4 million people and murdered seven doesn't deserve to be cut off from his family. Ravenclaw, multiplication backup?

Gryffindor smirked triumphantly. Ah ha, I knew you would argue that. In that sense, Voldemort should be a saint, since more than 99% of the Unbreakable Vow should be attributed to him. Anyone want to argue against that?

-Errr…

Harry wanted to give up. His inner characters had never been quite right ever since the Azkaban breakout.

-A smirking Gryffindor? What should Slytherin do, then?

Slytherin suggested timely, we should let Madam Bones sentence Lucius for three hundred and thirty years, and add some more years for things like torture, illegal animagus, money laundering, etc., only allow him to communicate with Draco with our consent, and monitor all their exchanges. This way, Lucius would alway be eager to use his mind and knowledge to our service, and we can make sure that Lucius won't have any bad influences on Draco.

We want a FRIEND! Hufflepuff screamed. Not a manipulated minion.

Harry needed a pencil and paper to figure this out. And, oh, the Vow. Harry needed to ask Hermione's opinion as well.

"Lord Malfoy, I need more time to decide. Vow requiress."

Lucius' face turned grey when he heard "Vow requiress". The man's voice betrayed some nervousness that he had never shown in front of Harry before. "Pleasse take all the time you need, Lord Potter."

Harry nodded, opened the suitcase door behind him, and called for Severus.

Chapter 15: Private Meeting

4:02 pm, June 24th, 1993

Second Private Meeting, Severus Snape

Harry sat on his personal couch - which did not look anywhere near a throne, just a regular muggle single person couch colored in Ravenclaw blue - and watched as Severus closed the suitcase door for the three Malfoys inside. When the ex-Potions master started to apply privacy spells toward the suitcase, Harry couldn't help but to ask, "Professor Snape, I didn't know that you are such good friends with the Malfoys."

Severus finished his spells, then turned to Harry and hissed. "I v-will sspeak truth in human lan-language. Too dif-ficult."

Harry nodded. That was a good idea for communication.

Severus took a seat on the couch across from Harry on the other side of a small table, and said. "As for your information, I wasn't this close with the Malfoys before. And that is one of the things that I need to tell you today."

Then Severus began to recount everything happened after he woke up from Voldemort's Hyakuju montauk curse. "After the pain on my Dark Mark woke me up from the hallucination and then subdued, I realized that the Dark Lord must have temporarily returned and was vanquished again. I initially wanted to contact Albus by my patronus to see if he needed any help, yet I found my patronus couldn't find him. I wanted to contact you, then I realized that I shouldn't try, because that might create a paradox if I wanted to go back in time to help you. Then I heard the explosion sound coming from the Forbidden Forest, and guessed that your hand might be involved. I decided to turn back an hour and check what happened in the Forbidden Forest, and to see if I could help. In order to facilitate my search in the forest, mostly against magical concealments, I -" The ex-Potions master cleared his throat and stared down hard at Harry. "I turned into my animagus form, and used my echolocation system to detect any discrepancies between visual and auditory images."

Harry used a whole second to understand what Severus really meant by "echolocation system" and "auditory images", then he had to use his perfect occlumency barrier to fight down his hysterical laughter, because, well, judging from Severus' stare, he might murder the Boy-Who-Lived right here and right now if Harry dared to laugh out loud.

-The resident bat in the dungeon is actually a BAT animagus!

Harry knew it was wrong to laugh at people's animagus form, which mostly reflected one's nature, but this was simply too hilarious, even his Hufflepuff side was laughing with tears.

When Harry finally managed to stop the laughing self behind the occlumency barrier, Severus already began to describe his unbelievable joy upon seeing the reconstruction of the Dark Lord's body with only blood and Hermione's body with only flesh. "It was then that I finally realized why both purebloods and muggles have the same custom as to preserve the deceased's hair, only that wizards would use magic to do the job better. It must be some reminiscent ritual from an era where resurection was quite common, and people could be revived with only a part of their body preserved. And luckily, I have your mother's hair preserved, as well as my own mother's."

Harry's heart sank. He had hoped against hope that Severus had stolen Lily's body or her head, and magically preserved it over the years. But no, it was only Lily's hair, which had no brain and no mind. Tears began to well up in Harry's eyes, and his lips quivered as he barely managed to speak. "Professor Snape, it doesn't, it doesn't actually work like that. You have to keep their brain cold immediately after their death, preserve the brain, and work from there."

Severus looked at Harry as if in shock. The man's voice lost its usual drawl, running rapidly as if searching for some alternative explanation. "But no, it, it - the Dark Lord only used his preserved blood to construct his own body. It doesn't need the brain."

"The, the Dark Lord had horcruxes, he used h-horcruxes to preserve his mind beyond death." Harry choked a bit. "And you, you saved Lucius' head, right?"

"I, I -" Severus looked at Harry in dawning horror, as if hope and happiness were crushed into dust in his black eyes, but the ex-Potions master hadn't given up yet. "If, if a single hair is enough for the polyjuice potion to shape a new body, including the head, why a hair is not enough for the ritual to reconstruct a new brain?"

Harry had to fight back his tears, and tried to control his voice. "I know polyjuice potion, the drinkers still think like themselves even they looked exactly like whoever the hair is from. I doubt the potion only reshapes the body, not the brain."

"You don't KNOW that!" The dark-haired potioneer spat. "An adult can polyjuice into a child, a man into a woman, and vice versa. Their brain sizes are surely different."

Harry then remembered that time when Severus drank polyjuice potion and changed into Harry. Hope and Rationalization began to argue inside Harry.

-What Severus said is true, we don't KNOW it, we just made an assumption and jumped to conclusion.

-But the probability is high. All a human being isis the brain, anything else can be repaired by magic. Otherwise, you would have to use something like the horcruxes. How could a hair possibly store all the memories and thoughts?

Blinking hard, Harry spoke against the screaming rationalist inside him. "Professor Snape, do you have evidence whether the brain changes into the hair donor after drinking polyjuice potion? Like a CT scan or something."

Severus frowned. "Muggle electronics do not work well around magic, Mr. Potter. I suspect if I get a CT scan, the machine won't produce any useful result. And I wouldn't advise you to put polyjuice potion into the mouths of muggles, because potions harmless to wizards can usually be lethal to muggles or even squibs. - Wait, I guess someone may already know the answer." Severus' words stopped here, and his eyes unreadable.

Harry had a sense that he shouldn't ask, but his Hope and Ravenclaw sides made him ask. "Who?"

Severus's lips twitched a bit before he answered in a flat tone. "Lord Grindelwald, his researchers, and perhaps some Americans and Russians after Dumbledore won the duel."

That answer sent a chill down Harry's spine.

-Actually, there are other ways to inspect the differences between two brains. For example, you can feed someone with polyjuice potion, then cut open the heads of both the drinker and hair donor to see for it yourself. Or, you can force a muggle to drink a polyjuice potion with the hair of another muggle regardless of the danger of the potion, and then see it on a muggle scanning device.

Harry gulped. All of a sudden, he remembered the horrible human experiments conducted by the Germans and Japanese during World War II, and sadly, how some of the data from the experiments had benefitted scientific research later on.

-Lord Grindelwald had allied with the Nazis. He used muggles in concentration camps to make himself invincible. Nazi muggle scientists might even helped to design experiments for him, using some scientific methods.

From a small corner of Harry's heart, Ravenclaw quietly suggested, even though we will never do the experiments ourselves, since the results are already there, why not try and get it? We are doing this for all humanity, remember? There could be other important knowledge there as well, right?

Severus pondered for a while, then spoke slowly. "I suppose wizards in some former Soviet states might be easier to persuade than the Russians and Americans."

Harry's Slytherin side jumped in. Grindelwald already did the experiments, and a lot of our potential enemies already knew the experimental results. There is no advantage that we can gain by not knowing what the enemies already knew. And by knowing, we can bring back everyone much faster, including Grindelwald's victims. We have infinite gold now, and Severus seems to be willing to do the bribery job for us.

It was fair to say that though Hufflepuff was screaming and Gryffindor was in righteous fury, Harry's Rationality side was quite tempted by the proposal. But again, Harry needed to ask Hermione's opinion. "Professor Snape, I need to take some time and think about it."

Severus hesitated, then nodded. "Fair -" The man suddenly stopped, then smiled with confidence and triumph. "Mr. Potter, I am afraid we have argued over a point that is irrelevant to the revival ritual. Although whether soul exists is up for debate, magical scholars all agree that wizards' thinking process can definitely continue without their original brain, or be discontinued with their brain intact. Animagi can think and act according to their own will inside the bodies of animals, where the brain sizes can vary greatly. Some wizards can even turn into something as small as a beetle. Whatever is there in the head of the beetle, it is not the original brain. But I do admit that the form of animal one adapted does have certain effects on one's primitive needs such as food preference. Moreover, it is widely known that dementor's kiss can suck one's soul out - or end their thinking process, depending on how to want to describe it - without any damage to the victim's physical existence. Therefore, I suspect the well-preserved brain may not play the central role for revival as you assumed."

Harry opened his mouth, then closed it again. He had to admit he had never pondered the relationship between mind and brain for wizards, and he didn't have enough time to read books written by magical scholars. The existence of animagi did suggest that the original brain was not a necessary condition for wizards to think; as for the dementor's kiss, Harry assumed no wizards - that was, perhaps besides Grindelwald's researchers - had cut open an victim's brain to see if some brain damage did occur, so it was inconclusive. Professor Quirrell did say that he craved a live mouse for food after being a snake, and he also said one could never quite disentangle the mind from the body it wore.

-But still, there is a big logic gap between an animagus' ability to think and the lack of necessity for a preserved brain in the ritual. Maybe I will teach Severus the scientific methods later.

Harry wanted to point this out to Severus, but the problem was, some part of Harry really wanted to agree with Severus. Harry looked at the smirking man, and sighed. "Professor Snape, the fact that wizards don't need their original brain to think when they are alive doesn't mean you don't need their original brain to make them think again without a horcrux. Plus, I guess even it was possible, the amount of magic required to reconstruct all the memory and thoughts someone had at the point of death must be massive, and I don't think the magic used in the ritual would suffice."

Severus first seemed to want to refute, but after he heard the last part, smirk slowly disappeared from his face. Harry could see the man's face turned grey, sorrow and remorse occupied the dark eyes, his shoulders slacked, and his back hunched a bit. The part of Harry that hoped Severus would offer some valid counter argument was squashed.

-I need to figure out how to retrieve the deceased's' memory and thoughts, or I need to tear apart reality and Time, whichever is easier.

"But reconstructing one's body is definitely a first step." Harry didn't want the man to destroy Lily and his own mother's hair in frustration and desperation, so he had to say this much.

Severus nodded gravely. After a while, the dark-haired man slowly resumed his composure, and continued his recount of that night. "Mr. Potter, I suppose, you know what happened later better than I do, since I only heard fragments of the conversation, the echolocation system didn't provide high quality images, and my eyes couldn't see much except false regular woods set up by the Dark Lord himself. However, the brightness of your patronus that you used to bring back Miss Granger was quite unique, I could see it with my poor eyes even through the magical concealments. But I do have a question concerning that, besides a little bit of life and magic, did you sacrifice the corporeal form of your patronus as well? Mine lost its corporeal form, but became really bright afterwards. Or am I not to know?"

Initially, Harry didn't know what Severus was talking about, then he realized: Severus must have upgraded his patronus from a Version 1.0 animal corporeal patronus to a Version 1.5 death-repellent non-corporeal patronus in the revival of Lucius without quite knowing why. Harry had told the secrets of the true patronus to Hermione, so she could use her true patronus to kill all the dementors in Azkaban. Judging from the fact that Severus already got a Version 1.5 patronus by accident, Harry didn't doubt that the man could perform a true patronus if Harry told him the secret. Harry hesitated before he replied. "There is some tricks about that. I suppose you can still use your patronus to communicate and everything, right?"

Severus nodded. "True. I think my patronus is even more powerful than before, and I feel it can easily drive dementors miles away, though it's hard to find a dementor and do the test these days. -Oh, is that how you destroyed the dementor brought to Hogwarts, and how Miss Granger destroyed the herd in Azkaban?"

-Well, Severus Snape is smart.

Severus pondered and said. "I suppose that's some riddle I need to solve for myself, but it's good to know that dementors and lethifolds are less of a threat to me."

"Also, though I guess it would be a poor comparison, did you become more friendly and more protective toward Miss Granger after you revived her in the ritual?" Severus frowned. "Or, is it because Lucius recognized multiple life debts to me regardless of the status of Snape family? I heard there is some old magic involved in life debts, that some sort of magical bond might be formed in the process. Or, is that simple human psychology that led to my growing care for Lucius, after I revived him and saved him a couple dozens of times? "

-Err…

Harry had no answer to that question. He was indeed more protective toward Hermione after she was revived, but that could be simple human psychology. And come to think of it, Hermione did owe him a life debt, and the part of ritual where Harry needed to put his life and magic into the patronus might have some effects as well.

"To be precise, I think I might have lost the will to kill Lucius." Severus sighed. "I wouldn't want to kill him before, but I think I could use the killing curse on Lucius if necessary. Now, I don't think I can kill him, at least not with the killing curse."

Harry could never use the killing curse on Hermione in the first place, so he had no idea whether it was the ritual at work, or Severus just became a better person, or Severus cared more about Lucius or about humanity in general.

Slytherin quietly suggested. That's a big side effect. If we want to use Severus as an assassin, we can't let him revive too many people. And we shouldn't revive too many people ourselves, either.

All the other parts of Harry screamed SHUT UP.

Harry decided to answer honestly. "Professor Snape, I already cared Hermione a lot before that day, so I have no idea."

"I would expect so." Severus nodded, and continued with his story of that night. "I have to say that I was quite shocked when I heard that you might destroy the world according to a Prophecy, and somewhat relieved when the Dark Lord forced you to take the Unbreakable Vow. Then later, as I heard you threatened the Dark Lord with massive explosion, I was almost scared to death. I thought you had a miniaturized nuclear weapon, or something with similar effects, and you might start a world-wide nuclear war."

Harry wanted to correct Severus' misconception about nuclear weapons, and decided against it. Harry had estimated in that night that there was no way an explosion caused by antimatter could be misinterpreted as a nuclear attack. And modern nuclear weapons and missiles had too many electronics in them that they couldn't possibly work properly around magic. But it wouldn't do Harry much good to deny it right away. On the other hand, Severus was a half-blood, he might read muggle books himself later.

Severus' dark eyes searched Harry's blank face, and continued. "I tried to fly into the graveyard to stop you, but I was stopped by Time. Obviously, the Dark Lord had set up some barrier to prohibit the graveyard's future to interact with its past. Then you struck all the Death Eaters and the Dark Lord with some magic that I still do not understand today, and you brought down the Dark Lord with some magical resonance between the two of you. The Time barrier disappeared as the Dark Lord lost consciousness. I fell to the ground as the pain from the Dark Mark almost made me pass out. Then," The ex-Death Eater's voice became less steady. "I saw Lucius' head right beside me. He wasn't really my friend back then, but he was someone that I could trust slightly above average, for the reason that you might have already guessed. I used cooling charms on his head, and the heads and partial heads of several others."

Harry was quite relieved when he heard this part. At least, the thirty-six accounts of life that Harry himself took could be easily brought back, or could it? "So you collected all the heads? How about Macnair and Quirrell? I mean, Quirinus Quirrell was innocent, he was just occupied by the Dark Lord. And Macnair tried to fight the Dark Lord."

Severus' eyes widened a little upon Harry's question, but answered smoothly, "I only have the ones that I didn't resent too much. I have Macnair's thumb, Quirrell's whole body, heads of Dolohov, Crabbe, Goyle, Rosier, Yaxley and Nott, and half heads of Mulciber and Sr. and Jr. Avery."

Harry was a little disappointed for this answer. However, eleven transfigured bodies plus one living Lucius, that was still better than none.

Severus expanded his answer. "And if you must know, I also have bodies of several muggles in my collection, but I am afraid all of them were brain-dead long before I got them, since the majority of them were nameless frozen bodies in muggle police morgues."

Ignoring the angry stares from all other parts for his previous suggestion, Slytherin had a good idea. Cunning people all have false identities ready at hand, we should do so as well. As Lucius indicated, it could be quite a lot of work, we'd better start soon. Ask Minerva to add an extra name on the list now and then, and ask Severus or Mad-Eye to look for nameless bodies in muggle morgues whose identity you can take.

But the construction of false identities could wait. "I assume you took the instruction the Dark Lord gave me, and made a copy?"

Severus nodded, and described how his time-turned self reminded him what to do; how he waited in the bathroom, swapped Harry's pouch, and took the Stone while Harry was changing; and how he used the duplication charm and the Stone to make duplicates of the instruction and the bodies. When time wasn't enough, he turned back another hour to make more transfigurations permanent, and finally duplicated the Stone itself. To the last part, Severus added in frustration, "Obviously, the power of the Stone is not something that could be transmitted so easily. I have tried it on several objects, a cat, and a dog, there was no problem before I used it in the ritual. However, the body of Lucius still came out the way it is now. The duplicate stone could stabilize Lucius for six to seven hours at the first time, then it became five hours, then four. Now, it is mostly my magic that is sustaining Lucius' life."

Harry's brain quickly generated several experiments to test the power level and the decay curve of the duplicated Stone, and that of duplicates of duplicates. And after some extrapolation, Harry might be able to estimate the power level of the original Stone, unless the extrapolation didn't work for the original Stone. Harry had been sort of worried over whether the Stone might slowly lose its power over intensive usage. Harry had read some theory on the Gemeo charm that the decay rate of duplicated object was dependent on the power of magic put into the charm and the size of the object. Severus was an exceptional potioneer, that meant he had excellent control of magic at all times, therefore, he might be a very good experimenter for this test - and a lot of other experiments that Harry and Hermione couldn't do yet.

Both Slytherin and Ravenclaw started to regret his decision to let Severus go freely one year ago, but Hufflepuff and Gryffindor shouted them down. Then Harry had an idea that he needed to test. "Professor Snape, can I have the duplicated Stone? I may need to study its properties."

Severus reached into his pouch, and handed Harry a red glass that looked quite similar to the original Stone, but the color was a little dull. "I just used it to stabilize Lucius before we came here. The power might return after six or more hours."

Harry put the duplicate into his regular pocket. "Thank you. I will test it later then. Please go on."

"As for my days in the past year, there is little that needs to be said. No magical law was broken except the usage of false identities and being an illegal animagus." Severus' voice took on a tone of sarcasm and grievance. " I guess reviving a dead Death Eater is rare enough that there is no law against that." He sighed. "I had been proud of myself for completing the ritual, but I never realized what I have done to the world until Lucius pointed it out to my face."

This part, Harry understood quite well now. Everyone in the world would want to know the secrets of revival, and who knew who they might choose to revive? Voldemort wasn't the only dark wizard who made horcruxes. Maybe some good people have destroyed fathers' bones of some dark lords, and rendered them unable to return. And this ritual could work in the dark lords' favor. What if some of the dark lords were so insane that they wanted to destroy the world? That was downright disaster.

Remorse was obvious in Severus' eyes and voice. "I should have thought of it, everyone would want to grab the power. And the potential enemies who wanted the Stone might have a much easier time in convincing their minions to risk their lives in the endeavor, since if they were successful, any lives lost in the attack could be restored."

-Oh, that as well. I need to spend some more time in my dark side to think about more avenues how revival could be dangerous.

There was a problem with that, Harry figured that by thinking about how the world could be destroyed, or just spending too much time in the dark side, he might increase his chances of causing the end of the world. Harry needed to ask for Hermione's opinion.

"In my blindness in the pursuit of power, and in my laughable ambition to walk the walks of Albus Dumbledore among others, I have neglected my duty in the Order as the dark wizard." Severus looked highly uncomfortable, somewhat reminding Harry of a student awaiting for reprimand from a teacher. "I should have stayed, and spent my time thinking like a dark wizard so that I could anticipate what they might do."

Harry didn't think there was anything wrong for Severus to try to become an extra powerful lord, as long as he didn't hurt anyone on his path. And Harry thought it would be bad for Severus to brew himself in the dark wizard mode for too long.

-And that was what Dumbledore made Severus and perhaps Mad-Eye do, or maybe these two just volunteered themselves. No wonder Severus was that snarky and Mad-Eye was that paranoid. Good people shouldn't be forced to do that.

There was a dull pain in Harry's heart, even if he knew it was necessary and right, even if he knew the personal happiness of two wizards was nothing as comparing to the number of lives they had already saved and might save in the future.

Don't forget we have a dark wizard and a bad person at our service for the next several hundred years. Slytherin suggested. We don't need to worry about Lucius going darker. Though we'd better let Severus and Mad-Eye check on the ideas proposed by Lucius.

Harry's face adapted some of the sternness of Albus Dumbledore, then softened. "Professor Snape, I don't want to let you spend too much time in the dark mode, but do you have any more ideas how the whole affair could be dangerous?"

Severus answered without hesitation. "If people know that even duplicated Stones can sustain transfiguration for up to a year, instead of using them to stabilize dying people so that they can be transport to the Hospital, they may use the duplicated Stones to sustain weapons. I heard the maintenance of nuclear weapons can be quite expensive so that a number of nations are considering to cut the stock of such weapons, but they are also worried that they may not have enough weapons when needed. As far as I know, the highest offices in most countries already knew about magic, and some might think to have contracts with powerful wizards, so that they can multiply their weapon stock as needed, and keep it there for a while with the duplicated Stones. I know that a lot of modern weapons with fancy electronics don't work well around magic, but I don't think the earlier models, such as those used by the Americans on the Japanese, could possibly contain too much electronics. Well, on the other hand, from what I heard about Chernobyl, nuclear things that do not work may cause more damage than those ones that work."

Harry almost gulped. That was an idea he had thought of before. It seemed Harry was not that unique. "How long did it take you to think of it?"

"One day when I was sleep deprived and magically exhausted, in the middle of trying to keep Lucius alive." Severus sighed. "I can certainly generate more if I get some rest."

-Well, it only took us a second. Regular smart people are not THAT creative.

Harry wasn't sure if he could take this as a comfort. There was also a question that Harry had to ask. "And how many wizards know about nuclear weapons or something like that?" Harry deliberately avoided the word "physics".

"Everyone who has spent enough time when their TV sets or radios are tuned to the news channel during the past fifty years. We have just ended a Cold War, Mr. Potter. Even the drug addicts in the ghetto where I grew up used 'the Soviets may nuke us all tomorrow' as an excuse for their behavior." Tiredness and frustration were in the silky voice of the half-blood wizard. "About five to six percent of the students in Hogwarts have non-magical parentage or upbringing, and I would assume the number to be similar for other countries. Therefore, about fifty to sixty thousand in total."

-And you don't need to be Harry or Voldemort to think of that. You just need to be Severus Snape.

Severus' face began to show desperation. "And in the thirty or so powerful lords in the world who are almost in par with Albus Dumbledore, at least two are known to have non-magical parentage, more might hide their family history. There are also lords like Grindelwald. I can hardly imagine Lord Grindelwald doesn't know how his muggle Japanese allies failed."

By this point, Harry was quite amazed that the world was still largely intact. Harry almost wanted to set up a Interdict of Harry now, so that no magic could be used around nuclear reactions or any fundamental particles in general. But no, Harry still needed to figure out how to use stars as fuels and how to conquer the galaxies.

-And I need to remind Auror Kingsley Shacklebolt that he should never give any good ideas to the muggle prime minister whom he is protecting.

That wasn't the end of Severus' words. "The worse thing is, among the several hundred to several thousand muggles in the highest offices who know about magic, a lot of them are reasonably intelligent, and some might even be creative. And according to some city legends in the United States, during the Cold War, both the American and the Russian muggles had used muggleborns in various experiments, and some wizards in the United States and Soviet Union might have participated. Considering the number of new spells crafted and the number of powerful lords emerged during the Cold War in those two countries, that could be true."

Harry felt sick. Harry had read about it somewhere that the United States government had deliberately spread syphillis and other sexual transmitted diseases in Guatemala in the 1940s, and in rural Alabama in black neighborhoods the 1970s, to test the epidemiology of such diseases. Therefore, there was no reason to believe that Germans or Japanese were particularly cruel, nor to believe Grindelwald's research was that unique. The British wizarding nobilities wanted to kill all muggleborns, elites in some other countries just found better uses for muggleborns, minorities, and citizens of some unimportant third world countries. Harry needed to optimize the world sooner.

The sternness and determination on Harry's face might have unnerved Severus, for the man quickly said, "I am sorry to disturb your thought so. I wonder if there is anything I could do."

Harry shook his head. It was Harry who had been too naive, and it was Harry who had deliberately avoided to think of such cruel things. Harry inhaled, and exhaled. "Professor Snape, thank you for letting me know. It's not decided yet, but would you mind to go on a trip to, say, Ukraine? You don't need to worry about cost or anything like that."

Severus composed himself from the previous desperation, and from his fear for the Boy-Who-Lived who scarily resembled Albus Dumbledore in his wrath. Severus bared his teeth with a bit of smirk. "My pleasure."

Harry realized Severus must have made himself quite a lot of gold and silver with the Stone, as a cunning Slytherin should.

Then, Severus looked a bit hesitant.

"What?" Harry didn't want to force Severus to do things that he didn't want to do.

Severus sighed. "Lucius is an expert in bribery and corrupting government officials."

-Oh, right, he cares about Lucius. I should really be careful about when and who to revive whom. For example, I can't let Mad-Eye revive people he might need to hunt down later. By the way, should I use Lucius on so many important matters?

Harry hesitated, and said, "I need to think about it."

"Then, I guess I have already received the answer to another question, but I have to ask. Lucius has invited me to be Draco's godfather. Lord Potter, according to your opinion, I should refuse it, right? " Severus said with some reluctance.

Harry noticed that Severus had just called him "Lord Potter", and the man seemed quite ready to serve another lord even if something the new lord desired was different from what he himself desired. Plus, Severus completely misunderstood what the previous hesitation was about. Harry was all about giving Draco more protection now after he talked with Lucius. "Oh, Professor Snape, of course you can become Draco's godfather if you want to. I am really happy for Draco and you."

Severus' eyes were perplexed for a while, then he said, "Thank you."

"And please call me Harry, or Mr. Potter, or Mr. Potter-Evans-Verres. Lord Potter is only reserved for very formal occasions." Harry added. He was OK being called as Lord Potter by Lucius, and Harry could act accordingly; but being called that by the ex-Potions master, or Professor Flitwick, or Professor Sprout? That was just bizarre. Plus, Harry needed to stay away from the image of "Dark Lord Harry".

Severus seemed to have worked up some courage from Harry's statements. "Mr. Potter, there is a matter that I may need to remind you to be more careful next time. It is about your theory on magical inheritance. Lucius had told me about what he heard from Draco when Draco was under Veritaserum. It seemed like you considered it a Mendelian inheritance of one single pair of gene. I happen to know some basics of the muggle genetic theory. According to your theory, a magical parent and a muggle parent can only give birth to a squib, and no squibs should be borned to wizarding families. According to what I know, my father was a muggle, or at least, he could be driven away by a muggle-repelling charm that I could master without a wand in my fifth year in Hogwarts."

Harry opened his mouth. He hadn't revisited his theory after the hasty session with Draco. He didn't even collect data for all types of couples, let alone trying to disprove his own theory. For such an important question, one hour with shreds of paper was obviously not enough. And according to Harry's theory, it was either that Severus had a mutation in the magical gene, or he was adopted, or his mother cheated, with much higher probabilities for the later two than the first one. "Professor Snape, I didn't mean to -"

"Personally, it is not a big insult to me, I didn't like my father anyway. However, I guess you have gathered why topics like this should be treated with more care. Draco was not an occlumens back then. Imagine what would happen if some 'good' fools accessed Draco's mind before Lucius did, and they might make this theory public for some greater good." A hint of sarcasm was in Severus' voice. "Either that you are right, and you will offend a lot of half-bloods who could be on your side, including Minerva, Trelawney and our new DADA teacher Lupin in the faculties, and Seamus Finnigan and Dean Thomas in your year alone; or you are wrong, and you will lose much credibility on other matters."

Harry nodded, and thanked Severus sincerely. "Professor Snape, thank you so much for telling me. You are right, I need to be more careful, and I will definitely reinvestigate my theory."

And that is our reward for not being a Dark Lord. Hufflepuff commented happily. Severus will never think to correct Voldemort's assumptions or to warn him to be more careful. As a result, Voldemort never knew two of his foremost Death Eaters could understand his hisses.

Ravenclaw echoed. Yeah, I also wonder how many other things Voldemort was wrong and nobody told him. And, come to think of it, Voldemort just withheld so much information from his followers that not even Bellatrix knew where he hid one of his many horcruxes. Otherwise, Bellatrix would have revived him years ago. By the way, we really need to revisit all our previous assumptions, discuss them with Hermione and/or Draco, discuss with Severus and Mad-Eye if necessary, and make a serious effort to disprove them. According to the number of names Severus just listed, it is possible that we already made a mistake. Not only the half-blood that Severus mentioned, if what Voldemort said in front of the SPHEW witches were true, he thought his father was a muggle as well.

The inner critic offered an alternative explanation. Or maybe none of the half-bloods know or tell others that their non-magical parents are actually squibs.

"Professor Snape, please do tell me everything that I might be wrong in the future." Harry said with all his sincerity. "And, umm, I have some books you can read after you get some rest. I can't imagine what you would be like with the books."

-At least, my book choices for Draco in his first year were no secrets now. So I'd better appear to be generous.

Severus slightly tilted his head.

Note:

Some basic inheritance data that Harry should collect before he could draw his conclusion on the AA-Aa-aa genetics:

1. The percentage of different phenotypes of children born to magical (AA) and muggle (aa) couples, which should be 100% squibs (Aa).

2. The percentage of different phenotypes of children born to magical (AA) and squib (Aa) couples. The result should be approximately 50% of magical children and 50% of squibs.

3. The percentage of different phenotypes of children born to squib (Aa) couples. The result should be approximately 25% of magical children (AA), 50% of squibs (Aa), and 25% muggles (aa).

4. The percentage of different phenotypes of children born to magical (AA) couples, which should be 100% magical (AA).

5. The percentage of different phenotypes of children born to squib (Aa) and muggle (aa) couples, which should be 50% squibs and 50% muggles.

6. To be precise, Harry also need to collect data to see the percentage of squib/muggle children born to muggleborn, half-blood, and pureblood couples.

Harry only collected less than 20% of the basic data he needed from a very small sampling pool, and he jumped to the conclusion that suited his taste. Plus, Harry didn't know the possibility that some of the squib parents in his sampling pool could actually be magical, and their magic was suppressed for some reason. Ariana Dumbledore and Merope Gaunt had both been considered as squibs by some others, but they were both witches. Any scientific journal should reject Harry's paper within 10 minutes.

The next update will be 6 pm (EDT), 04/11/2015.

Chapter 16: Interlude, Draco

5:21 pm, June 24th, 1993

Interlude, Draco Malfoy

Draco cherished every second that he could spend with both his parents, he really did. But this was a rather awkward moment that Draco wanted to run away from.

"So you have been seeing Miss Padma Patil privately for several times?" Father smiled while petting Draco's coiling snake patronus on his lap. "I have seen her fighting beside you, a cunning and powerful witch indeed."

Mother grabbed Draco's hand. "Oh, Draco my dear, why don't you tell me earlier? I was thinking about the two Greengrass girls, but your opinion is the decisive one. You should invite Miss Patil home sometimes."

-Ahh…

"Cissy, I have looked up Miss Patil's lineage since I knew she was Draco's lieutenant," Father patted Draco's shoulder approvingly, and then reached for Mother's hand. "All magical up to her grandparents. I need to write more letters to my contacts in India for further information."

-Err, Father looked up Padma's family history when I was in my first year? Father, you don't need to be that prepared.

"Draco, by the way, do you know her caste? I heard Brahmins are priests in India, therefore more likely to be wizards, or of higher social status." Father asked another question that Draco didn't know how to answer.

By this point, Draco just wanted to hide his face in his hands: Father, I know you are a pureblood supremacist, I didn't know you are a supremacist in other accounts as well. Oh, Merlin. This IS Father. What can I do?

Just as Mother asked, and Father explained what the caste system was, and why Patil was such a common last name that Father's contacts in India couldn't decide her caste just from her surname, the suitcase door was opened.

Draco was both disappointed and guiltily relieved to see Severus by the door. The dark-haired man appeared both tired and happy. "Lucius, I think I will accept your invitation now."

"Oh, Severus, my brother and best friend," Father stood up and walked toward Severus with open arms. "We are really going to be family now."

Mother was a bit confused. She asked Draco with a whisper, "What invitation?"

Father's footsteps stopped, his arm in mid-air, and he answered with a bit of awkwardness in his voice, "Cissy, I - I haven't have a chance to tell you, I invited Severus to be Draco's godfather."

The dark-haired man walking down the stairs became quite awkward as well. "Mrs. Malfoy, if -"

"Oh, my dear Severus," Mother smiled at Severus while sending a glare toward Father, "Draco will be so lucky as to have you as his godfather."

From Harry's training, Draco knew the reason that Father never asked Mother's opinion on such familial matters was not that Father didn't respect Mother or something like that. It was because Mother hadn't been in Father's decision-making system for eleven years, and human beings simply did not update their decision patterns that quickly. However, Draco was not sure how Mother would take this.

Father cleared his throat, showed Severus the couch and said, "Severus, why don't we do it now? I can draft the paperwork, and -" Father looked up at Harry, who was now standing outside of the suitcase door, "Lord Potter, would you like to be one of the witnesses?"

"Yes, I would be happy to." Harry answered cheerfully. "By the way, how many witnesses do you need?"

"Two." Father answered.

"Hermione will be here in a moment." Harry eyed Father pointedly.

Father tilted his head graciously. "It would be a great honor for House Malfoy to have Lady Granger as the second witness."

"Then I will talk with Hermione first, so she won't be too surprised to see you." Harry said. "And Professor Snape, I will need you to lift the seal of the room and reseal it again when Hermione comes. Now I will leave you four here for a private moment."

"It is so considerate of you, Lord Potter." Father said politely.

As the suitcase door was closed from outside, Father began to draft paperwork, Mother offered Severus tea, and asked lightly, "Severus, as Draco's godfather, your opinion will be highly valued in the topic we were at before you came in. Do you happen to have any recollections on Miss Padma Patil?"

-Ahherrr… Can we discuss the end of the world or something like that?

The next chapter will be up at 6 pm (EDT), 04/12/2015.

Chapter 22: The Man of Many Names

6:21 am, June 28th, 1993

In a luxurious modern apartment near the Square Mile of London, a middle-aged man sat by a large office table in the study. Lamplight reflected off of his balding head as he stared at the past year's collection of the Daily Prophet over his brown moustache, his face bearing an expression of complete disbelief. His left hand fumbled awkwardly for his long-forgotten coffee on the table, as if it was only a prosthetic hand made of metal and plastic; and his right hand waved a black wand with amazing deftness and precision. "Accio Quibbler."

-This has to be kidding. Not even that boy could be this stupid, not even Dumbledore could reach this level of insanity. And if what the paper said is true, how is the world not on fire?

After flipping through The Quibbler, American Mage, Toronto Magical Tribune, and Magical Pravda, the middle-aged man, known to some as Alexander Chernyshov, others as Jeremy Jaffe, some as Matsumoto Taro, while a certain boy might recognize him by magical resonance as Tom Riddle, sighed in complete frustration.

-I know I was an exceptional idiot when I was twelve, I know Dumbledore is completely insane, and I have studied the minds of delusional patients in St. Mungo's, but what the boy did is beyond my wildest imagination. Providing service of the Stone to the entire wizarding world, what was he thinking?! Every powerful wizard in the world, no matter what they pretend to be or whether they consider themselves as Light or Dark, would drop their masks and pursue it! Perenelle was only able to keep the Stone for six hundred years because she pretended that the power of the Stone had great limitations, such as only being able to extend your life for a few decades, and spreading rumors such as infertility after using the Stone - as evidenced by the fact that she and Flamel never had any kids. And now, after a bunch of dying witches and wizards successfully had babies after returning to their twenties by the Stone, is there anything left that can prohibit the mundane idiots from wanting it?

And as the man turned to his next obvious question, he felt a worse headache than he'd had last night when he saw Crystal Camblebunker's petrified body and found Nagini missing: why is the world still standing today?

The man could easily envision hundreds of ways how the world and maybe even the universe might come to the end - the books that boy lent him gave him some extra ideas - but he could not even figure out one reason why magical Britain was still largely intact today.

-Surely, some powerful lords in the world would be wise enough to reach agreements with each other while the others were still squabbling. They can always rob the Stone from Azkaban/Hogwarts/Department of Mysteries first, and try to kill each other later. Or, is my estimation of human nature too optimistic again?

There was also the question that what the hell happened on that night. Being a Version 1.0 horcrux as the boy might name him, the man only knew what Tom Riddle did and intended to do as of 6:26 am, June 13th, 1992, but he had no idea what really happened after that.

The man knew for sure that the ridiculous story given by the "vision" of the Boy-Who-Lived was something made up by the younger Tom Riddle in great haste. Although he did plan to revive the Granger girl, he had no plan to sacrifice all the Death Eaters, so that part must be the hand of that boy. He could hardly fathom how the simultaneous beheadings could be done if certain books given to him by that boy hadn't given him some ideas.

-Probably the boy transfigured some anesthetic/poisonous gas that he himself had antidote, and then he did the beheadings later. Or maybe Mad-Eye Moody did it for him.

And thinking along that line, it was easy to explain why his Version 2.0 horcruxes were not activated the moment Tom Riddle was vanquished - because he didn't die, per se. Perhaps Moody had crucioed the original Tom Riddle into insanity, or obliviated him, or used some other magic, or made him brain-dead as called by the muggle medical book, or all of the above.

That could also partially explain Lucius Malfoy's sudden reappearance. He remembered his plan to force the boy to take an Unbreakable Vow that he would not destroy the world, and Lucius would be the binder. The Daily Prophet said that Lucius' reluctance for the sacrifice the Dark Lord asked was the reason the ritual failed, and Lucius was a snake animagus.

-Then things make sense now. The younger Tom Riddle is an heir of Slytherin as well. The treacherous Malfoy had already signed a deal with the Boy-Who-Lived, and these two might know that they could communicate in Parseltongue. So while the original Tom Riddle thought that Parseltongue conversation was private and safe, if Potter wanted Lucius to understand what the two Tom Riddles conversed in Parseltongue, Lucius could. Therefore, the boy and the elder Malfoy might have coordinated their moves, the boy used the magical resonance between Tom Riddles to temporarily disable the Dark Lord, while Lucius would use some gas or magical device to disable the other Death Eaters.

-Oh, if everything went as planned, the boy still had one more hour in his Time-turner, so he could plan ahead with Lucius, and all Lucius needed was some cue from the boy, then he could act. And Lucius probably didn't die at all. He just laid low for a year, then came out again as the boy needed some blatantly stupid bait to get Bellatrix.

-Well, maybe the bait isn't that stupid if I let Bellatrix run loose like the last time. She might think whatever the boy said in the newspaper is a new order for her, and just turn herself in. Or, she might break into the Ministry of Magic to kill Lucius for revenge. It is so hard to balance your servants' loyalty and their intelligence.

-Maybe the younger Tom Riddle told Lucius that I was behind the attempted murder of his son, and I have planned to use that attempted murder to frame him, in Parseltongue, of course. Lucius might seek revenge. Moreover, the reward for Lucius' treason is also quite obvious: Narcissa. Hmm, I have never thought Lucius would care so much about his wife. Did he hold grudge against me when I refused to enact revenge for Narcissa's supposed death?

-Ordinary fools, Lucius Malfoy and Severus Snape alike. Admittedly, Bellatrix is pretty much like that as well. On the other hand, this part of human nature is something that I have not fully comprehended, and therefore not fully exploited earlier.

-And since Lucius presented himself as the Number Two enemy of the Dark Lord, and a bait for Bellatrix, I will surely grant his wish after I get my power back and after I have killed the younger Tom Riddle. I will make sure to kill his wife and son slowly and creatively in front of him, and then enjoy some other creative ways on Lucius. But that can wait.

With one of the biggest mysteries solved, the man turned to the next impending question: how can I get my power back?

Before making this particular horcrux with Helga Hufflepuff's cup, Tom Riddle had thought of the fact that a Version 1.0 horcrux would not be able to understand the powerful magic that he wielded, so he had transferred all his knowledge to his basilisk pet Nagini, and arranged Crystal to look after it. He had to order Nagini not to petrify or kill Crystal, of course. However, when he went to Dean Forest last night, he had only found a stone statue of Crystal, and Nagini was no longer there. He caught a snake nearby, and asked what had happened.

The stupid non-magical creature answered: "The Crown of Sserpent ordered all ssnakess to tell all bassilisskss and powerful magical ssnakess to go to Hogwartss discreetly. The caretaker woman tried to sstop Nagini, sso Nagini killed her."

Tom Riddle immediately killed the snake and used a vanishing spell on the body, for any snake might report to the younger Tom Riddle, and he doubted if the memory charms that he could manage at this time could fool the minions of his younger self.

-It seems that boy has overcome his reluctance in creating sapient beings, and began to utilize snakes as messengers. Hmm, he might want to gather all powerful magical snakes, and to see if any of them has the same knowledge as Herpo did. A very logical and clever approach indeed.

-Ah, the boy might have figured out my backup plan as to use the combination of a Version 1.0 horcrux and a basilisk from there. Nagini must have just got Hogwarts, for the boy only started to use Lucius as a bait a few days ago.

-Damn, I have ordered Nagini not to give knowledge to anyone but me, yet the boy is another Tom Riddle, and another Heir of Slytherin. The boy must know the secrets of a lot of powerful magics by now. I need to kill that boy before he tells the secrets to more people. However, considering the boy's exceptional stupidity in dealing with the Stone, maybe even Lucius has been taught some protection spells that I created by now.

-I need to regain my power, fast.

-Hmm, since any of my orders can be overridden by the younger Tom Riddle, if I get a hold on Nagini, I can override the boy's orders as well. Yeah, the boy has probably figured this out already, and he may think Nagini is a more subtle bait for me, and have arranged traps for me in Hogwarts. However, I never said that I only have one pet snake, did I? As I'm going to Albania soon, the stupid Nagini can wait for its punishment. I just need to get to the Dark Forest before the boy's order gets there. But before that, I need a place to plan and prepare.

Therefore, the man was now in his luxurious condo in a modern apartment complex near the Center of London, where it was least likely to contain the spying eyes of snakes. He needed to plan more carefully this time round, and he needed some more physical strength before the long-distance portkey traveling.

-The potions to remove Bellatrix's character from her body did work, but that woman had certainly skipped quite a number of meals and had lost the track of time in the meanwhile. And now, I am temporarily trapped in this weakened body as an unpleasant side effect. Also, if she had grabbed onto my cup earlier, I might have be able to catch Nagini before the stupid snake got to Hogwarts.

The man sighed, and continued his planning.

The next Chapter will be up at 6 pm (EDT), 04/23/2015.